Register of the Aleksandr Polovet͡s papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Aleksandr Polovet͡s papers
1966-2016
2017C55
Hoover Institution Archives
12 manuscript boxes, 7 oversize boxes (13.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, printed matter, and audiovisual material relating to Russian literature and to Russian émigré affairs.
Polovet͡s, Aleksandr, 1935-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual or digital material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2017.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1935 July 12 Born, Moscow, Union of Soviet Socialist Republics
1955 Graduated from Moscow Poligraficheskii Tekhnikum
1955-1958 Military service
1971 Received master's degree in Patent Information, Central Institute of Patent Studies
1976 Immigrated to the United States
1976-1980 Quality control supervisor, Western Lithograph
1977 Founded Almanac Publishing House
1980-2000 Founder, editor-in-chief of Panorama newspaper
1980s-present Vice President, later President, of Media Analysis Foundation
1983 Naturalized United States citizen
1991-present Founder and President of the Bulat Okudzhava USA Cultural Fund
Scope and Content of Collection
This collection documents the professional life of Alexander Polovet͡s as a journalist, editor, and publisher of Panorama, one of the major Russian-language publications founded by Jewish immigrants from the Soviet Union.
Polovet͡s' correspondence is of special interest to literary scholars of the Third Wave, as it includes letters from authors such as Vasily Aksyonov, Yuz Aleshkovsky, Sergei Dovlatov, Anatoly Gladilin, Igor Guberman, Edward Limonov, and Vladimir Maximov. The collection is also of note since it includes photographs of authors and audio files of conversations with them. This also applies to other cultural and political figures.
An extensive file of photographs, and sound and video recordings chronicles Alexander Polovet͡s’ friendship with Bulat Okudzhava.
Audiotapes.; Russia (Federation)--Civilization.; Russian literature.; Russians--United States.; Soviet Union--Emigration and immigration.; Video tapes.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1990-2015
  Scope and Contents note
  Bio-bibliographical material, birthday greeting, identification papers, interviews, and press coverage, arranged by physical form.
  - Bio-bibliographical material, 2015 (Box-folder 1: 1)
    Untitled compilation containing his brief biography, family information, bibliography of his works, excerpts from reviews of his books, and information on his friendship with Bulat Okudzhava.
  - Birthday greetings
    Congratulatory articles on the occasion of his 65th and 80th birthdays. See also: OVERSIZE FILE.
    - "Aleksandru Borisovichu Polovtsu – 80 let! Nashi pozdravleniia!" PEN-Rossii, printout, 2015 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - Grich, Aleksandr. "Chelovek iz legendy. K 80-letiiu Aleksandra Polovtsa," Prazhskii Telegraf, No. 7, printout, 2015 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - Grich, Aleksandr. "Chelovek-legenda. K 80-letiiu Aleksandra Polovtsa," Kol’tso A, No. 88, printout, 2015 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Identification papers, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    Press passes issued to Alexander Polovets. Photocopies.
  - Interviews and press coverage
    Arranged chronologically. See also: OVERSIZE FILE.
    - Hendrix, Kathleen. "Soviet Emigres Making Own News," Los Angeles Times, photocopy, 1990 November 20 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - Tsyvina, Irina. "Iz zhizni emigrantov," Ekho planety (Moscow), No. 49, 1997 November-December (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - Waxman, Henry A. "Tribute to Panorama and Alexander Polovets," Congressional Record, photocopy, 2000 June 20 (Box-folder 1: 8)
    - Limonov, Eduard. "Tikhii ocean / Venis bich," Kniga vody, photocopy, 2002 (Box-folder 1: 9)
    - Dovlatov, Sergei. "Velichestvennaia 'Panorama'," Rech' bez povoda…, ili Kolonka redaktora, Moscow, photocopy, 2006 (Box-folder 1: 10)
    - "Avtorskii katalog: Aleksandr Polovets," Sem iskusstv, 2014 (Box-folder 1: 11)
      Printout from http://7iskusstv.com/Avtory/Polovec.htp.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1977-2009, undated
  Arrangement Statement
  Letters arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent.
  - General and unidentified, 1977-2009, undated
    - A-M, 1981-1999, undated (Box-folder 1: 12)
    - N-Z, 1984-2009, undated (Box-folder 1: 13)
    - Unidentified, 1977-1995, undated (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Adamov, Yuri, 1992, undated (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Aikhenvald, Iurii, 1992 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Aksyonov, Vasily P., 1981-1999, undated (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Alburt, Lev, 1981-1992, undated (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Alekhanov, Sergey, 1989 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Aleksin, Anatolii, 1998-1999, undated (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Aleshkovsky, Yuz, 1983-1992, undated (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - Alova, Alla, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - Antonow (Broide-Trepper), Denis A., 1987-1988 (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Armalinsky, Mikhail, 1988 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Aroutoonyan, Karo, undated (1993) (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Arsantov, Sasha (aka Alexander Yurovsky), 1986-1994, undated (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - Artamonov, Sergei, 1999, undated (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - Asarkan, Alexander, 1984-2000, undated (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - Asherovsky, Ilya, undated (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Askol'dov, Aleksandr, 1989-1995, undated (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Avtorkhanov, Abdurakhman, 1987-1998, undated (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Babyonyshev, Sarra, 1989, undated (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Badasch, Semen, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Batchev (Batshev), Vladimir, 1989-1996 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Belinkov-Yablokoff, Natalia, 1993-2009, undated (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Belotserkovsky, Vadim, 1990-1992, undated (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Berezhkov, Valentin M., 1997-1998 (Box-folder 2: 9)
    Also includes two articles about Berezhkov.
  - Bobyshev, Dmitri, 1990-1992, undated (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Boldyrev, Peter, 1986 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Bolshun, Boris, 1986 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - Borodin, Andrei, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Burichin (Burikhin), Igor, 1986 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - Chanyshev, Arsenii, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Chemiakin (Shemiakin), Mihail, 1997 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Cheporov, E., 1991 (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Chertok, Shimon, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - Chudakova, Marietta, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - Chuprinin, Sergei, 1994-2000 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - David, Itzhac, 1991 (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - Dimont, Igor, 1988 (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - Dovlatov, Sergei, 1984-1992, undated (Box-folder 2: 23)
    Also includes some articles about Dovlatov.
  - Draitser, Emil, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 2: 24)
  - Druzhnikov, Yuri, 1988-1994 (Box-folder 2: 25)
  - Edel, Ernst, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 2: 26)
  - Efimov, Igor, 1984-1994 (Box-folder 2: 27)
  - Ekkel, Bibs, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 2: 28)
  - Emelyanov, Oleg, 1986 (Box-folder 2: 29)
  - Erofeyev, Victor, 1989-1996, undated (Box-folder 2: 30)
  - Ershov, E., undated (Box-folder 2: 31)
  - Evelson, Evgeniia, 1984-1985, undated (Box-folder 2: 32)
  - Eventov, Jacob (Yakov), 1984-1988 (Box-folder 2: 33)
  - Ezersky, Bella, 1983, undated (Box-folder 2: 34)
  - Fedoseyev, Anatoly, 1983-1994 (Box-folder 2: 35)
  - Fedotov, Michail, 1988, undated (Box-folder 2: 36)
  - Felshtinsky, Yuri, undated (Box-folder 2: 37)
  - Fistein, Jefim, 1985-1986, undated (Box-folder 2: 38)
  - Foster, Ludmila, 1983-1996 (Box-folder 2: 39)
  - Frumkin, Vladimir, 1992 (Box-folder 2: 40)
  - Gabay, Henry, 1984 (Box-folder 2: 41)
  - Gagen, Tat'iana, 1993 (Box-folder 2: 42)
  - Gast'ev, Iurii, 1993, undated (Box-folder 2: 43)
  - Gendlin, Leonard and Mira, 1987 (Box-folder 2: 44)
  - Gershlovin, Valeriy and Rimma Gershlovina, 1988 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Gessen, Yelena, 1985 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Gladilin, Anatoly, 1989-2001, undated (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Golovsky, Valerii, 1989-1990, undated (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Gorodetskii, Igor', 1982-1989 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Grafov, Eduard, 1983-1994, undated (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Grivnina, Irina, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Grobman, Michail, 1984, undated (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Gubenko, Iakov, 1994-1996, undated (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Guberman, Igor, 1993-1998, undated (Box-folder 3: 10-11)
  - Guidoni, Alexander, 1989 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Ioffe, Solomon H., 1987-1988 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Itzelev, Leonid, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - Ivanov, Alexander, undated (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - Ivanov, Vyacheslav Vsevolodovich ("Koma"), 1994, undated (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - Kafanova, Ludmilla, undated (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - Kamianov, Boris (aka Baruch Avni), 1977-1996, undated (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - Kandel, Feliks (pseudonym Kamov, Feliks), 1987-1999 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - Kapianidze, V., 1990 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - Karaulov, Andrei, 1992 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Kashin, Nicolai, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 3: 22)
  - Kasparov, Gary, 1990 (Box-folder 3: 23)
    Envelope only.
  - Kataev, Pavel Valentinovich, 1992 (Box-folder 3: 24)
  - Kazakova, Regina, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 3: 25)
  - Kenjeev (Kenzheev), Bakhyt, 1993 (Box-folder 3: 26)
  - Khaiutin, Mikhail, 1988 (Box-folder 3: 27)
  - Khalif, Lev, 1984-2009 (Box-folder 3: 28)
  - Kharkovsky, Alex, undated (1984) (Box-folder 3: 29)
  - Khazanova, Marina, 1991, undated (Box-folder 3: 30)
  - Kichin, Valery, 1996-1998, undated (Box-folder 3: 31)
  - Kislik, Vladimir, 1991 (Box-folder 3: 32)
  - Klimontovich, Nikolai, 1992 (Box-folder 3: 33)
  - Komar & Melamid (Vitaly Komar and Alexander Melamid), 1989-1990 (Box-folder 3: 34)
  - Kontsevaia, Emma, 1990 (Box-folder 3: 35)
  - Kopeliovich, Vladimir, 1988 (Box-folder 3: 36)
  - Kopelman, Simon, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 3: 37)
  - Korotich, Vitaly, 1989-1999, undated (Box-folder 3: 38)
  - Korzhavin, Naum, 1992 (Box-folder 3: 39)
  - Kotliarov, Vladimir (stage name Tolsty), 1981-1992, undated (Box-folder 3: 40-41)
    Also includes brochures, invitations, photographs, and issues of Vechernii zvon.
  - Kovalev, Konstantin, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Kreyd, Vadim, 1985-1991, undated (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Krichevskii, I., 1993 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Krotkov, Yuri, 1981 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Ktorova, Alla, 1985-1994 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Kukui, Valery, 1988 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Kumykov, Iu., undated (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Kunin, Wladimir, 1995-1999, undated (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Kuzminsky, Konstantin K., 1979-1998, undated (Box-folder 4: 9-10)
  - Kvirikadze, Irakli, 1993-1994, undated (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Lamm, Nikolai, 1993, undated (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Lamm-Levkova, Inna, undated (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Larsky, Lev, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Lazaris, Vladimir, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Lebedev, Valerii, undated (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Leikin, Pavel, 1987 (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - Lemkhin, Mikhail, 1984-2014, undated (Box-folder 4: 18)
  - Levin, Vadim, 1993, undated (Box-folder 4: 19)
  - Levintov, Aleksandr, 1998 (Box-folder 4: 20)
  - Levkov, Il'ia, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - Levykin, Viacheslav, 1989 (Box-folder 4: 22)
  - Limonov, Edward, 1981-1995, undated (Box-folder 4: 23)
  - Losev, Lev, 1987-1996 (Box-folder 4: 24)
  - Lotovskii, Iakov, 1992, undated (Box-folder 4: 25)
  - Luryi, Yuri I., 1988 (Box-folder 4: 26)
  - Lvov, Arkadii, 1990-1994, undated (Box-folder 4: 27)
  - Maclis (Makhlis), Leonard, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 4: 28)
  - Maksimova, Ol'ga, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 4: 29)
  - Mamleyev, Yuri, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 30)
  - Manin, Eugene, 1986-1996, undated (Box-folder 4: 31)
  - Markish, David, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 4: 32)
  - Marshinina, Tatiana, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 33)
  - Maruta, Oleg, 1993 (Box-folder 4: 34)
  - Maximov, Vladimir, 1983-1994, undated (Box-folder 4: 35)
  - Mechik, David, 1983-1985, undated (Box-folder 4: 36)
  - Medvedeva, Natalya, 1983-1992, undated (Box-folder 4: 37)
  - Michelet, Michel, 1982-1990 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Mihajlov, Mihajlo, 1986-1988, undated (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Miloslavsky, Iurii, 1983 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Mitta, A., undated (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Mukhametshin, Boris, 1985-1992, undated (Box-folder 5: 5)
    See also: Kotliarov, Vladimir.
  - Muravieva, Irina, undated (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Muravnik, Maiia, 1991-1992, undated (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Nagrodski, Jouri, 1987, undated (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Nahapetov, Rodion, undated (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Nakleushev, Evgenii, 1988, undated (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Navrozov, Lev, 1986-1995, undated (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Nevin, A., 1988, undated (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Neznansky, Fridrikh, 1986 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Nossik, Boris M., undated (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Nudelman, Rafail, 1989-1991, undated (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Ocheretiansky, Alexander, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Ouspenskaia (Uspenskaia), Tatiana, 1994-1995, undated (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - Papernyi, I., 1990-1994 (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - Papirova-Andelman, Marina, 1993 (Box-folder 5: 19)
  - Paramonov, Boris, 1983-1984, undated (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - Parkhomovskii, Sergei, 1992, undated (Box-folder 5: 21)
  - Pavlovsky, Eugenia, 1989 (Box-folder 5: 22)
  - Perelman, Victor, 1992-1996, undated (Box-folder 5: 23)
  - Pirlikh, Andrei, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 5: 24)
  - Pomerantsev, Igor', 1986-1987 (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - Popov, Evgenii, 1993-1999, undated (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - Popovsky, Mark, 1985-2000, undated (Box-folder 5: 27)
  - Posel'skii, Iasha, 1996 (Box-folder 5: 28)
  - Proffer, Carl, 1981-1984, undated (Box-folder 5: 29)
  - Prokhorova, I., 1991-1994 (Box-folder 5: 30)
  - Puchinian, Stepan, 1992 (Box-folder 5: 31)
  - Pudina, Liubava, 1995, undated (Box-folder 5: 32)
  - Puschkarsky, Nikolai, 1984-1985, undated (Box-folder 5: 33)
  - Pyatigorsky, R., 1989 (Box-folder 5: 34)
  - Radyshevskii, D., undated (Box-folder 5: 35)
  - Reznik, Semyon, 1986-2000, undated (Box-folder 5: 36)
  - Rein, Evgenii, 1992 (Box-folder 5: 37)
  - Rovner, Arkady, 1987-1999, undated (Box-folder 5: 38)
  - Roziner, Felix, 1985-1999, undated (Box-folder 5: 39)
  - Rozovsky, Mark, 1993, undated (Box-folder 5: 40)
  - Rubina, Dina, 2000 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Rudakov, Nikolai, A., 1988 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Rudiak, Ilya, undated (1984) (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Rybakov, Anatoli, 1995 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Ryskin, Grigorii, 1984, undated (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Sagalovsky, Naum, 1985-1991, undated (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Sapguir, Kira, 1986-1999, undated (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Savitski, Dmitri, 1984-1988, undated (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Schuman, Tomas David, 1987-1993, undated (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Scriabine, Helene, 1982-1991 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Shakhnovich, Genrih L., 1984-1987 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Shamir, Israel, undated (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - Shamkovich, Leonid, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Sharogorodsky, Lev, 1983-1993, undated (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - Sharov, Andrei, 1991-1992, undated (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - Shaternikova,Marianna, 1996 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - Sheynes, Boris and Marina, 1984 (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - Shifrin, Avraham, 1984, undated (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - Shlaen, Boris, 1978-1990 (Box-folder 6: 19)
    Also includes copies of three of his articles.
  - Shrayer, Maxim, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - Shrayer-Petrov, David, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 6: 21)
  - Shtromas, Alexander and Violeta, 1983-1999, undated (Box-folder 6: 22)
  - Shulman, Sol, 1989 (Box-folder 6: 23)
  - Sichkin, Boris M., 1998, undated (Box-folder 6: 24)
  - Skachinsky, Alexander, 1981 (Box-folder 6: 25)
  - Slavinskii, Mikhail, 1986 (Box-folder 6: 26)
  - Slepakov, Maria and Vladimir, undated (Box-folder 6: 27)
  - Slivkin, Evgenii, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 6: 28)
  - Smekhov, Veniamin, 1995-1999, undated (Box-folder 6: 29)
  - Sokolov, Sasha, 1981-2015, undated (Box-folder 6: 30)
  - Solovyov, Vladimir, 1987-1998, undated (Box-folder 6: 31)
  - Sotnikova, Emma, 1992, undated (Box-folder 6: 32)
  - Strelianyi, A., 1990 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Sumarokova, Irina, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Suprunenko, Iurii, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Suslov, Ilya, 1981-1999, undated (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Svetlov, Felix V., 1987 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Svirskii, Grigorii, 1987-1992, undated (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Sztein, Emanuel (aka Edward), 1981-2000, undated (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - Tarkington, Maiia, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Topol, Edward, 1993-1997, undated (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Troll, Julia, 1985, undated (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Tsvetkov, Aleksei, undated (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Ufliand, Vladimir, 1989-1993, undated (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - Vail, Peter and Alexander Genis, 1985-1997, undated (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - Vaisman, M., undated (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - Vaksman, Gregory E., 1987-1988 (Box-folder 7: 15)
  - Valdberg, Genadi, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - Valk, Gabriel, 1991 (Box-folder 7: 17)
  - Vapnik, M., 1988-1989 (Box-folder 7: 18)
  - Veghin, Pyotr V., 1989-1993, undated (Box-folder 7: 19)
  - Vilenskaia, L., 1984 (Box-folder 7: 20)
  - Vins, Georgii, undated (Box-folder 7: 21)
  - Vishnevskii, Vladimir, 1990-1992, undated (Box-folder 7: 22)
  - Vladimov, Georgii, 1986-1996, undated (Box-folder 7: 23)
  - Voldman, Gregory, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 7: 24)
  - Vul'fovich, Iosif L., 1986 (Box-folder 7: 25)
  - Weeks, Albert L., 1982-1993 (Box-folder 7: 26)
  - Werner, Arthur A., 1986-1990, undated (Box-folder 7: 27)
  - Yakovlev, Yegor, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 7: 28)
  - Yankovskaia, Sonia, 1992 (Box-folder 7: 29)
  - Yarim-Ageev, Yuri, 1983 (Box-folder 7: 30)
  - Yevtushenko, Yevgeny, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 7: 31)
  - Yupp, Mikhail, 1990-1991, undated (Box-folder 7: 32)
  - Zel'tser, P., 1986-1989 (Box-folder 7: 33)
    Also includes a copy of one of his articles.
  - Zholkovsky, Alexander, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 7: 34)
  - Zhurbin, Alexander, 1990 (Box-folder 7: 35)
  - Zinik, Zinovy, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 7: 36)
- WRITINGS, 1968-2015, undated
  Newspaper articles and other writings, arranged into sets by Alexander Polovet͡s and chronologically by issue date within each set.
  - Set 1 - Publications in the Soviet Union prior to immigration, 1968
    See also: DOUBLE OVERSIZE FILE.
    - "Ne izobretat’ izobretennoe," Neftianik, No. 10, printed copy, 1968 October (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - "Razmnozhenie patentnoi dokumentatsii," Voprosy izobretatel’stva, No. 10, printed copy, 1968 October (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - Set 2 – Publications in Panorama (Los Angeles, CA), 1980-2009, undated
    See also: OVERSIZE FILE.
    - "Los-Andzheles – N’iu-Iork," Panorama, photocopy, undated (1980) (Box-folder 8: 3)
    - "Voprosy est’? Pis’mo v redaktsiiu," Panorama, photocopy, 1980 November (Box-folder 8: 4)
      Written under the pseudonym of "K. Pitonov."
    - "I byl kontsert," Panorama, No. 117, photocopy, 1983 July 8-15 (Box-folder 8: 5)
    - "Ogorodnikovy arestovany," Panorama, No. 182, photocopy, 1984 October 5-12 (Box-folder 8: 6)
    - "O pol'ze gazetnykh podshivok," Panorama, No. 183, photocopy, 1984 October 12-19 (Box-folder 8: 7)
    - "Vse dni zhizni svoei. Pamiati Aleksandra Shargorodskogo," clipping, 2000 (Box-folder 8: 8)
    - "Proshchanie s ‘Panoramoi’,", 2000 July 1 (Box-folder 8: 9)
      Typed copy of general letter addressed to authors, readers and staff of Panorama.
    - "BP. Mezhdu proshlym i budushchim. Glavy iz knigi," Panorama, No. 1454, 2009 February 18-24 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Set 3 - Publications in Post-Soviet Russia and Russian-language press in the United States, 2003-2014
    Also includes an interview with Alexander Polovet͡s. See also: OVERSIZE FILE and DOUBLE OVERSIZE FILE.
    - "Teatr absurda," Energiia Vostoka (Moscow), No. 4 (19), printed copy, 2003 (Box-folder 8: 11)
    - "I togda on skazal Stalinu…," Ofitsery (Moscow), No. 3, printed copy, 2005 May - June (Box-folder 8: 12)
      Interview with Valentin Berezhkov.
    - "…Proshchai, Moskva," Vmeste (Walnut Creek, CA), No. 195, printed copy, 2013 October (Box-folder 8: 13)
    - "Khraniat tak mnogo dorogogo," printout, 2014 November 18 (Box-folder 8: 14)
      http://soyuzpisateley.ru.ph?n=news&id=298
  - Set 4 - Publications in the Russian-language press in the United States, other countries, and on the Internet, 2003-2015, undated
    - "My imeem tot literaturnyi protsess, kotoryi my imeem…," Vestnik (Baltimore, MD), No. 23, printed copy, 2003 November 12 (Box-folder 8: 15)
    - "Diplomatiia – nauka tonkaia," Vestnik (Baltimore, MD), No. 1, photocopy, 2004 January 7 (Box-folder 8: 16)
    - "TsDL i okrestnosti," Vmeste (Walnut Creek, CA), No. 100, printed copy, 2005 October (Box-folder 8: 17)
    - "Russkaia periodika v SShA," Russkii iazyk v tsentre Evropy (Banska Bistritsa, Slovakia), No. 11, pp. 109-111, printed copy, 2008 (Box-folder 8: 18)
    - "O knige Liudmily Kafanovoi ‘Liubov’ i mistika’," Chaika (Owings Mills, MD), No. 19, clipping, 2009 October 1-15 (Box-folder 8: 19)
    - "Pod shorokh patefona…," Chaika (Owings Mills, MD), No. 8, pp. 44-49, and No. 9, pp. 51-54, printed copies, 2014 April 16-30 and May 1-15 (Box-folder 8: 20)
    - "Vena-Rim-Amerika. 1976-i," Chaika (Owings Mills, MD), No. 12, pp. 56-58 and 74, printed copy, 2014 June 16-30 (Box-folder 8: 21)
    - "Anna Semenovna," Sem’ iskusstv, No. 10, color photocopy, 2014 October (Box-folder 8: 22)
    - "Est’ v druzhbe schast’e ogolteloe… – K 80-letiiu Anatoliia Gladilina," Chaika, 2015 September 4 (Box-folder 8: 23)
      Color printout from http://www.chayka.org/node/6698
- REVIEWS OF ALEXANDER POLOVETS' BOOKS, 1995-2014, undated
  Miscellaneous reviews and announcements of books by Alexander Polovet͡s and some other publicity about him, arranged into sets by Polovet͡s and chronologically by issue date within each set.
  - Set 1 – Publications in Panorama
    - "Knigoliuby – vnimanie!," Panorama, No. 1383, photocopy, 2007 October 10-16 (Box-folder 8: 24)
  - Set 2 – Publications in other newspapers and magazines
    See also: OVERSIZE FILE and DOUBLE OVERSIZE FILE.
    - Aleksin, Aleksei. "Dlia chego ty zdes',", 1999 (Box-folder 8: 25)
    - Fruta, Stanislav. "O chem pishet velikii russkii?," Vestnik (Cockeyesville, MD), No. 19, printed copy, 2004 September 15 (Box-folder 8: 26)
    - "Begletsy i drugie 'geroi'," Literaturnaia gazeta, No. 36, 2006 September 6-12 (Box-folder 8: 27)
    - Kollarova, Eva. Russkie kul’turnye issledovaniia, Banska Bistritsa (Slovakia), printed copy, 2007 (Box-folder 8: 28)
    - Kuzoleva,Tat'iana. "Bratislavskie vstrechi. Russko-slovatskii dialog kul'tur," Russkii iazyk v tsentre Evropy (Banska Bistritsa, Slovakia), No. 10, printed copy, 2007 (Box-folder 8: 29)
    - Kafanova, Liudmila. "Liubov' i mistika," Chaika (Owings Mills, MD), No. 12, printed copy, 2008 June 16-30 (Box-folder 8: 30)
    - Kuznetsova, Anna. "Dni i knigi," Znamia, No. 4, printed copy, 2009 April (Box-folder 8: 31)
    - Nerpina, Galina. "Kogda vozvrashchaetsia veter," Iunost’ (Moscow), No. 5, printed copy, 2009 May (Box-folder 8: 32)
    - Gelein, Aleksei. "Obladaia talantom, nado stat' emigrantom. Razmyshleniia o proshlom i vospominaniia o budushchem po obe storony granits," Nezavisimaia gazeta, No. 1404, printed copy, 2009 April 9 (Box-folder 8: 33)
    - Flyers for presentations of new books by Alexander Polovet͡s and other events organized by him, 2009-2014, undated (Box-folder 8: 34)
    - Safronova, Elena. "Parodiia bez shutok," Nezavisimaiia gazeta, 2009 September 10 (Box-folder 8: 35)